# Nicholas Emmanuel Chimaobi

## **SUMMARY**

I'm an experienced Full-stack web developer with 1+ years of strong and intuitive problem-solving skills, proficient in React.js, Node.js, Ruby on Rails, communication, collaboration, and adaptability to perform well in a team. I am seeking opportunities to utilize my technical skills and continue my development as a Full Stack Web Developer.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# MICROVERSE, Remote

# Mentor (Volunteer), May 2022 - Present

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on maintaining motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

# New Horizon, Lagos, Nigeria Intern, July 2021 till November 2021

- Debugged and fixed defects in the codebase.
- Collaborated with the development team to understand project requirements and identify solutions.
- Participated in code reviews to ensure that the code meets standards and best practices.
- Developing and testing new features and functionality.

#### **EDUCATION**

# MICROVERSE, May 2022 – January 2023

## Full Remote Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

# NEW HORIZON, January 2021 – June 2021 Remote Graphics Designer, Full-Time

- Spent 1000+ hours mastering layout, wireframes, and Figma designs while simultaneously creating designs with Adobe XD, Photoshop, Canva, and Powerpoint.
- Developed skills in remote programming using Upwork, industry-standard, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

nicholasemmanuel321@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn Twitter | Medium | Portfolio

#### **SKILLS**

### **Front-End:**

JavaScript, React, Redux, SCSS, Next.js, Typescript, Tailwind CSS,

#### Back-End:

Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, Node, Express, MongoDB

#### **Tools & Methods:**

Git, GitHub, Heroku, Mobile Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

#### **Professional:**

Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

# **PROJECTS**

## **LazyCoders App**

- -Microverse is a web app where a user can checkout mentors and schedule a session with mentors.
- Built with (React JS, CSS, CoinRankingAPI, and AOS Animation)
- Visit-site: Live Preview

## **Free To Game**

- Free to the game is an API-based project for all game lovers. Users can like and give their insight by commenting.
- **Built with** (Javascript, CSS, API, and Jest-testing)
- Visit-site: Live Preview

# **Car Rentals**

- Exotic car rental is a car rental agency that primarily serves people who require a temporary vehicle. Users can create an account, log in and book or reserve a car for a specific period of time..
- **Built with** (Javascript, React, Redux, Ruby on Rails, tailwind CSS, and Gitflow)
- Visit-site: Live Preview

